<idea-plugin>
    <id>Shortcut Trainer</id>

    <name>Shortcut Trainer</name>
    <vendor>Leif Hanack</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        <idea-plugin>
            <description>
                <h1>Shortcut Trainer for IntelliJ IDEA</h1>
                <p>Improve your efficiency with IntelliJ IDEA by learning and practicing keyboard shortcuts with the Shortcut Trainer plugin.</p>

                <h2>Features</h2>
                <ul>
                    <li><strong>Random Shortcut Challenge</strong>: Engage with a pop-up that prompts you with a description of a random shortcut from your current keymap.</li>
                    <li><strong>Solution Reveal</strong>: Not sure what the shortcut is? Reveal the solution with a simple keystroke.</li>
                    <li><strong>Continuous Learning</strong>: Move on to the next shortcut challenge to continue learning without interruption.</li>
                </ul>

                <h2>Usage</h2>
                <ol>
                    <li><strong>Start Training</strong>: You can start the Shortcut Trainer in two ways:
                        <ul>
                            <li><strong>Keyboard Shortcut</strong>: Press <strong>Cmd-Shift-P</strong> on macOS or <strong>Ctrl-Shift-P</strong> on Windows/Linux to begin training.</li>
                            <li><strong>Help Menu</strong>: Alternatively, you can start it from the IntelliJ IDEA <strong>Help</strong> menu. Navigate to <strong>Help</strong>Help &gt; <strong>Shortcut Trainer</strong>.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li><strong>Reveal Answer</strong>: If you're unsure of the shortcut, you can press the <strong>Show</strong> button or use <strong>Opt-S</strong> (macOS) or <strong>Alt-S</strong> (Windows/Linux).</li>
                    <li><strong>Next Challenge</strong>: Click <strong>Next</strong> or use <strong>Opt-N</strong> (macOS) or <strong>Alt-N</strong> (Windows/Linux) to move to the next challenge.</li>
                </ol>

                <h2>Preview</h2>
                <p><img src="https://github.com/leifhanack/intellijidea-shortcut-trainer/blob/main/shortcut-trainer.png?raw=true" alt="Shortcut Trainer Preview" width="600"/></p>
                <p>Learn more about the functionality and enjoy the process of mastering your IntelliJ IDEA shortcuts!</p>

                <h2>Installation</h2>
                <p>You can easily install the Shortcut Trainer plugin either from the JetBrains Plugin Marketplace online or directly from within IntelliJ IDEA. Follow these steps based on your preference:</p>
                <h3>From JetBrains Plugin Marketplace:</h3>
                <ol>
                    <li>Go to the <a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com">JetBrains Plugin Marketplace</a>.</li>
                    <li>Search for <strong>Shortcut Trainer</strong>.</li>
                    <li>Find the plugin in the search results and click on it.</li>
                    <li>Follow the instructions to install it into your IDE.</li>
                </ol>
                <h3>From IntelliJ IDEA:</h3>
                <ol>
                    <li>Open IntelliJ IDEA and access the <strong>Settings</strong> dialog.</li>
                    <li>Navigate to <strong>Plugins</strong>.</li>
                    <li>Switch to the <strong>Marketplace</strong> tab.</li>
                    <li>In the search bar, type <strong>Shortcut Trainer</strong> and press Enter.</li>
                    <li>Find the plugin in the search results and click <strong>Install</strong>.</li>
                </ol>

                <h2>Contributing</h2>
                <p>Your contributions are welcome! If you'd like to help improve the Shortcut Trainer, please feel free to submit pull requests, report bugs, or suggest new features.</p>

                <h2>License</h2>
                <p>This plugin is open-sourced under the MIT License. See the <a href="LICENSE.md">LICENSE</a> file for more details.</p>

                <p>Happy Coding!</p>
                <p>Leif Hanack</p>
            </description>
        </idea-plugin>
    ]]></description>

    <actions>
        <action id="strug.intellijidea.shortcuttrainer.ShortcutTrainer"
                class="strug.intellijidea.shortcuttrainer.ShortcutTrainer" text="Shortcut Trainer">
            <add-to-group group-id="HelpMenu" anchor="first"/>
            <keyboard-shortcut first-keystroke="control shift P" keymap="$default"/>
        </action>
    </actions>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
    </extensions>
</idea-plugin>